Finding Aid for the Bound Manuscripts Collection LSC.0170
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Bound Manuscripts
  - Calendar from a liturgical book. St Jean de Baillon, Parchment 18 leaves. Title and heading by Francis Denis Beautort. 12 large initials in red ink. Signed, dated and written (probably the calendar rather than the added notes) by Father Denis Beautort, priest of the church of St Jean de Baillon (near Luzarches, north of Paris toward Chantilly)., December 1, 1470.; *170/697; In a contemporary limp parchment wrapper too small for the calendar.
  - Prayers. In French and Latin. North-west France (Brittany?), Written by one person in an angular French textura script., ca. 1450.; 170/698; Parchment. 48 leaves. 59 gold initials on blue, red and white grounds, 6 grotesque initials. Bound in 18th century Italian colored paper covers embossed with flowers. Formerly part of a larger manuscript.
  - Statutes and Ordinances of the Order of St Michael. In French. France (probably Paris), Written by one person in batarde script. Full page miniature (f. 7) with architectural border of a king (originally Louis XI, now Francis I) enthroned and attended by his court. Attributed to a painter in the circle of the Master of the Paris Entries, possibly Etienne Collaud. One of a series of twelve manuscripts of the Statutes commmissioned by Francis I between 1523 and 1528. Bookplate of Hemricout de Ramiol (ca 1810, Liege), and Howel Wills (1845-1901). Sotheby's July 11, 1894, no.1104, bought by Ellis., 1523-28.; 170/700; Parchment. 42 leaves. Bound in dark blue velvet over pasteboards, bront and back detached.
  - Document roll. Pisa(?), Italy, 1326-27. A commercial agreement in Italian. Sold by Bonhams & Brooks March 13, 2001, no.429., ***170/701; Parchment (two membranes) 825 × 160-175 mm.